ipreo.com 2019-05-15

# Ipreo Privacy and Cookie Policies

## IPREO PRIVACY POLICY

This website landing page (this **“Site”** ) is brought to you by the Ipreo LLC and the Ipreo group companies, which include Ipreo Limited and Ipreo Data Inc. ( **“Ipreo,” “we”** or **“us”** ).

This privacy policy ( **“Privacy Policy”** ) applies to personal information collected in connection with your use of this Site. Use of this Site is governed by our Public Sites Terms of Use. Ipreo operates various other websites that offer access to an array of services, products and information provided by Ipreo to its customers. Personal information collected in connection with the use of any of such other Ipreo websites is governed by the website’s applicable privacy policy.

This Privacy Policy describes how Ipreo treats information you provide to us, or which we otherwise collect, which can directly or indirectly identify you ( **“Personal Information”** ), how we may use your Personal Information, how we protect the security of your Personal Information and how you may change or request that we amend your Personal Information on our systems. To the extent Personal Information is governed and protected by European Union ( **“EU”** ) and/or UK data protection laws (such Personal Information is hereinafter referred to as **“EU Personal Information”** ) we will ensure that we comply with all relevant EU and/or UK data protection laws when processing such EU Personal Information.

The Personal Information that we intend to process includes your name, business phone number, business postal address, business email address, and your IP address, and where appropriate, dietary requirements.

Ipreo respects the privacy of its Site visitors and strives to protect the security of the Personal Information it processes.

Click the link below for Ipreo’s policy on each topic:

How and When We Collect and Use Personal Information  
Our Purposes for Processing  
Our Use of Cookies  
Marketing  
How we Share your Personal Information  
How we Protect the Security of your Personal Information  
Children’s Privacy  
Your Rights Regarding your Personal Information  
Other Websites  
Changes to this Privacy Policy  
How to Contact us

### How and When We Collect and Use Personal Information

We may collect the following Personal Information:

(a) Information you give us. We collect your name, business phone number, business email address, business postal address and company name that you provide when you contact us regarding any services, data, products, white-papers and information Ipreo provides (the **“Products”** ), including when you request information regarding us or any of the Products described on this Site, and/or when you add such information to register for, or respond to an invitation to, an Ipreo sponsored or related event (an “Event”). In addition, when appropriate in connection with certain Events, we may collect information regarding your dietary requirements.

We may use this Personal Information provided by you on this Site to respond to your specific requests for information about the Products and other inquiries, and/or where applicable, in connection with an Event. We may also use the Personal Information you provide when you request information about a Product or an Event to inform you about other Products and Events that might be of interest to you and to gather feedback from you on this Site and the Products.

(b) Information we get from your use of this Site. When you access this Site, our systems automatically record information such as your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, mobile device identifier, browser type and characteristics, and whether and how frequently you use this Site and request information regarding the Products available through this Site.

We process this Personal Information to understand users’ preferences, to better serve users, and to improve this Site and the Products.

(c) Aggregated Information. We may collect information regarding use of this Site, or about a category of users of this Site, or information about attendees at an Event, and combine that information with other information pertaining to use of this Site and the Products by you and other users, or as applicable, other information pertaining to attendance at an Event by you and other attendees. Such aggregated information will not include any Personal Information, and may be used by Ipreo in connection with its provision of the Products or its sponsorship of Events, and for other Ipreo business purposes.

### Grounds for Processing Personal Information

The Personal Information that we may need to process includes your name, business phone number, business postal address, business email address and your IP address. We need such Personal Information primarily to enhance your experience with the Site, to enable us to comply with your request for Product information, to enable us to comply with legal obligations, for the purpose of addressing a system or security issue, or a suspected violation of the Public Site Terms of Use or the law and, in many cases we may use your Personal Information to pursue our legitimate interests, provided your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. The situations in which we will process your Personal Information for our legitimate interests include some or all of the following:

(a) To enhance, modify, personalize or otherwise improve and support the Products and this Site.

(b) To update and maintain the accuracy of Personal Information.

(c) To enhance network and information security, including preventing unauthorised access to our computer and electronic communications systems and preventing malicious software distribution.

(d) To conduct data analytics studies to review and better understand how users interact with this Site.

(e) To provide Product-related news and other news and information that we believe may be of interest to you, our customers, other companies and businesses

Whenever we process Personal Information for these purposes we ensure that we keep your Personal Information rights in high regard and take account these rights. You have the right to object to this processing if you wish, and if you do wish to do so please submit a request via our [Privacy Request Form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/5d202a6a-cc93-48e7-9bb0-6c4b64d2b1a1). Please bear in mind that if you do object and we cannot demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing your Personal Information, we will stop processing your Personal Information which may affect our ability to provide you with certain services and carry out tasks to your benefit. Please also see your rights regarding your Personal Information in 8. _“Your rights Regarding your Personal Information”_ below.

As part of its services, Ipreo collects, licenses and uses information regarding individuals and companies in the global capital markets community. It is possible that you and some of your contacts may be part of the global capital markets community, and information about you and some of your contacts may appear in our licensed databases. Please be assured that individual entries in our licensed databases are independently collected by the Ipreo research department and do not come from data that is received from users’ use of our Site.

### Our Use of Cookies

We use cookies, which are small data files that this Site may transfer to your browser. You can find more information about cookies at websites such as www.allaboutcookies.org and www.youronlinechoices.eu. For more information on what cookies Ipreo use and why, please see our Cookie Policy below.

### Marketing

As stated above, Ipreo may use your Personal Information you provide when you contact us regarding any of the Products or an Event, to contact you regarding the Products and we may send you Product-related news and other news and information that we believe may be of interest to your organization and/or business. If you wish to unsubscribe from these communications, please [click here](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/5d202a6a-cc93-48e7-9bb0-6c4b64d2b1a1).

If you unsubscribe from direct marketing, we may still need to process some limited Personal Information in order to ensure that you receive no further marketing communications. We may also still send you important administrative messages as part of your ongoing use of our products and services (including the Products).

We will separately obtain express consent from you before contacting you whenever we are required to do so by applicable law (such as the Canadian “anti-spam” law and EU data protection laws).

(a) Among Ipreo Group Companies: We may share Personal Information among the Ipreo companies described above for purposes of providing the information you request about the Products and in support of this Site, and occasionally, to contact you (subject to any applicable legal requirements) regarding additional products and services that may be of interest to you.

(b) With Third Party Service Providers: We may provide your Personal Information to our third party service providers so that they may assist us in connection with operating this Site or conducting an Event. We typically enter into written contracts with our third party service providers, require them to use Personal Information only for that purpose and require assurances that they will appropriately protect Personal Information entrusted to them.

(c) With Business Partners: We may share your Personal Information that you provide to register for, or respond to an invitation to, an Event, with co-sponsors or organizers of the Event, and we may share your Personal Information you provide to download a Product, with any co-authors or co-providers of the Product. These business partners may use the Personal Information in connection with the applicable Event or Product and/or, when appropriate, to send you information about products or services that may be of interest to you.

(d) For Law Enforcement and Legal Purposes: We may disclose your Personal Information as we deem necessary or appropriate: (i) under applicable law, (ii) to comply with legal process; (iii) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (iv) to enforce our Public Site Terms of Use; (v) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (vi) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or those of our affiliates, you or others; and (vii) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

(e) Transfers outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”): The sharing of your EU Personal Information as described above may involve the transfer of your EU Personal Information outside the EEA, including to and in the United States. By submitting your Personal Information, you consent to such transfers and processing. Whenever we transfer any EU Personal Information outside the EEA we will put in place an adequate level of protection to ensure that any such transfers comply, and are consistent, with applicable EU and/or UK data protection laws, including with respect to transfers among Ipreo affiliates, the standard data protection clauses adopted by the EU Commission. If you require further information about this protective measure, you can request it from our Data Protection Team by submitting a [Privacy Request Form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/5d202a6a-cc93-48e7-9bb0-6c4b64d2b1a1).

### How we Protect the Security of your Personal Information

We are committed to maintaining the security of Personal Information. We employ reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to secure and protect Personal Information collected as described in this Privacy Policy from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. We permit persons working for us to access and use the Personal Information you provide only to serve legitimate business and service needs consistent with this Privacy Policy. We also require our third party service providers to implement appropriate security measures. Please remember, though, that no method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us (see 11 _“How to Contact Us”_ below). We retain Personal Information for as long as we reasonably require it for legal, business or contractual purposes. In determining data retention periods, we take into consideration local laws, contractual obligations, our reasonable business requirements and your reasonable expectations and requirements. When we no longer need Personal Information, we securely delete or destroy it.

### Children's Privacy

Minors under the age of 18 should not provide any information to us using this Site or the Products. We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 18.

### Your rights Regarding your Personal Information

You may have the right to access the EU Personal Information that we process about you and to request that we correct, amend, or delete it if it is inaccurate or processed in breach of applicable laws. These rights may not apply in some cases and, if you make a request, we shall inform you if that is the case. If you would like to request access to, or a correction or amendment to, your EU Personal Information or request deletion of your EU Personal Information, please submit a request via our [Privacy Request Form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/5d202a6a-cc93-48e7-9bb0-6c4b64d2b1a1).

### Other Websites

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information collected in connection with your use of this Site and the Products. Information submitted on a third party website linked to this Site is subject to the terms of the privacy Policy applicable to such third party website, and not the terms of this Privacy Policy. Ipreo is not associated with these third party websites and does not review their privacy policies. We cannot guarantee the privacy of any information that may be obtained by third parties at these other websites. We strongly encourage you to review the privacy policy of any website you visit before supplying personal information through that website.

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to address new or revised website functionality, new or revised aspects of the Products, Internet technology, or applicable law. The handling of Personal Information is governed by the version of this Privacy Policy in effect when such information is received. Therefore, you should review it from time to time to be sure that you are aware of the most up-to-date applicable provisions. Your continued use of this Site and the Products after we have posted changes to this Privacy Policy indicates your agreement to the amended terms of this Privacy Policy.

### How to Contact Us

Ipreo Limited and the Ipreo entities that process the Personal Information may be contacted via our [Privacy Request Form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/5d202a6a-cc93-48e7-9bb0-6c4b64d2b1a1). The Ipreo group comprise entities and offices in the UK, US, APAC and South Africa.

Your questions, comments and feedback are very important to us. For privacy-related issues or questions, please contact us via our[Privacy Request Form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/5d202a6a-cc93-48e7-9bb0-6c4b64d2b1a1).

We will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints or disputes we receive regarding the processing of your Personal Information. To the extent your Personal Information is EU Personal Information, and you are unsatisfied with the resolution of any complaint, you may contact the [UK Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/) for further information and assistance.

Effective Date: February 5, 2019

Version: M3.1

## IPREO COOKIES POLICY

We use "cookies," which are small data files that this Site may transfer to your browser.

### 1\. Types of cookies

Generally, the cookies we use fall into the following two categories:

(a) "Strictly necessary cookies" which are essential for you to move around within this Site and for the operation of the Site.

(b) "Performance cookies" which analyze how our users use this Site and monitor Site performance.

Within these two categories, we currently use or may use in the future the following types of cookies:

(a) Session cookies (temporary cookies that expire when you log off this Site or when your session automatically times out) to maintain your session and maintain security and verify details while you use the Site as you navigate from page to page.

(b) Persistent cookies (cookies stored on your browser between sessions) to help uniquely recognize you or your browser and remember how you have used the Site. In addition to cookies that send information to us, this Site may also permit use of cookies to collect information and send it to third parties for analytical purposes, to permit functionality on the Site, or to help with authentication (see below).

### 2\. Functionality services we use

This Site may make use of Google Maps, Google Site Search, Microsoft’s Bing Maps, or other third party services, which may place cookies on your browser and collect IP address and browser data and related information in order to facilitate functionality and to maintain and improve the quality, security and integrity of the third party services. In some instances, the third party services may make use of web beacons to help deliver cookies and compile usage information. Data collected by third parties are subject to those third parties’ own privacy policies.

### 3\. Analytics and marketing services we use

In addition, this Site may use analytics features such as services provided by Google Analytics, Ion Interactive, and Daddy Analytics, as well as marketing software tools such as the email tools provided by Marketo. Cookies placed on your browser by such services may collect limited information pertaining to your use of the Site, including traffic and usage data. In accordance with the applicable service terms, such services do not collect personal information. Use of data collected by analytics services (generally, in aggregate form only) is subject to the service’s own privacy policies. Note that Google offers a Google Analytics browser add-on (designed to be compatible only with certain browsers) to provide website visitors the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.

We do not collect personal information about your online activities across third party websites or online services, and thus this Site does not respond to web-browser “do-not-track” signals or other similar mechanisms. We do not permit our third party service providers to collect information from this Site for other websites other than as described in the preceding paragraph.

### 4\. Controlling and deleting cookies

If you want to control or delete the cookies we set, you can do this through your browser settings. The ‘help’ function within your browser should tell you how. However, restricting cookies may affect your use of this Site and prevent some services and selection tools from working.
